-我要走了  -别走  他会来的
- I gotta go. - No, no. He'll be here.
我保证他只是迟到一会儿而已
I'm sure he's just running a little late.
他取消过两次检查了  他不会...
He's canceled two exams. He's not gonna...
-他怕你  -自然
- He's scared of you. - Sure.
害怕老婆玩过的男人  有道理
The ex-boy toy. Yeah, that makes sense.
-他以前不怕你的  -是啊
- He wasn't scared before. - Right.
你认为怕我是某严重小恙的症状之一吗
You think being afraid of me is a symptom of a serious ailment?
突发情绪波动  回归幼稚心态  腹痛
Sudden mood swings, infantile regression, abdominal pain.
他还昏厥过两次
He's passed out twice.
是的  我觉得他可能是生病了
Yeah, I think it might be a medical problem.
-他迟到20分钟  我要走了  -拜托
- He's 20 minutes late. I'm out of here. - Please.
-他会来的  -凭什么这么肯定
- He'll be here. - Why?
因为他爱你  你说的话他都会听
Because he loves you and does everything he's told?
因为我没告诉他你要来
Because I didn't tell him you'd be here.
-他喜欢能看见   -是啊
- He likes to see. - Yes, he does.
史黛西
Stace?
怎么回事
What's going on?
你好  我是格雷戈·豪斯  你一定是马特
Hi. I'm Greg House. You must be Matt.
-是马克  -马克·华纳  不必起来
- Mark. - Mark Warner. Don't get up.
- 抱歉  开家长会  -没关系
- Sorry. Parent conferences. - It's okay.
格雷戈·豪斯
Wow. Greg House.
不是有意躲你
No, I haven't been avoiding you.
我只是不想浪费你的时间
I just didn't want to waste your time.
其他医生给我检查过了  压力太大而已
The other doctors checked me out. They said it was just stress.
开始报考大学了  学生和家长都围着我
College season. Kids, parents... they're all over me.
可以理解
Makes sense to me.
-格雷戈  -不然你要我怎么做
- Greg. - What do you want me to do?
你说会给他做检查
You said you'd check him out.
他自称健康  有什么好检查的
He says he's healthy. What's to check out?
给你添麻烦了
Sorry for the mix-up,
不过你们有机会叙叙旧我很高兴
but I'm glad you two got a chance to catch up.
-你们看起来聊得很开心  -真是高手
- Looks like you're having fun. - Oh, he's good.
装真诚能这么像  其他更不用说
If you can fake sincerity, you can fake pretty much anything.
我对你老公的景仰无以言表了
I can't tell you how much I like your fella.
彼此彼此
Yeah, me too.
你看  我就知道你会挖苦我
You know, I thought you'd be all sarcastic.
还铆足了劲儿  因为我娶了史黛西
Bitter, you know, because Stacy married me.
我们该一起出去玩
We should do things together.
打打球什么的  男人的娱乐
Maybe throw a ball around or something. Guy stuff.
我们可以一起去跑跑步[讽刺豪斯瘸腿]
We could go for a run together.
真有奥斯卡·王尔德范呀
Ah! It's Oscar Wilde.
看你们争风吃醋我真是开心
This pissing contest is really turning me on.
他需要去医院
He needs to go to the hospital.
敬女人  忍不了  杀不得
Here's to women. Can't live with 'em, you can't kill 'em
总不能告诉邻居她去大西洋城跳脱衣舞了
and tell the neighbors they're stripping in Atlantic City.
太对了
Damn straight.
-我比你高  -我头发比你多
- I'm definitely taller. - I have more hair.
而且我认为...
And I think that...
马克
Mark?
-有人叫急救车去普波教学医院吗  -这里
- Someone call 911 for a wagon to Princeton Plainsboro? - Garson!
-怎么回事  -不要紧的
- What happened? - It's okay,
女士们先生们  不必担心
ladies and gentlemen. Nothing to worry about.
-除非你们也吃了小牛肉  -你给他下药了
- Unless you had the veal. - You dosed him.
我答应你要给他检查嘛
I told you I'd check him out.
我还有点担心救护车会在他晕倒之前赶来呢
I was a little worried they were gonna get here before he passed out.
那样骗他喝酒就更难了
Would have been tougher to get him to drink.
你可以搭我的车  我们谈谈
I'll give you a ride. We can talk.
肚子痛  脾气暴躁  没有明显病因
A tummy ache, cranky... no apparent source.
有何见解
Any thoughts?
福曼  有话要说吗
Foreman, you're gonna contribute,
还是你偷车偷累了
or are you too tired from stealing cars?
我在模仿豪斯  不好笑吗
I'm being House. It's funny.
好笑  我笑得牛奶都从鼻子里喷出来了
I know. You made milk come out of my nose.
早  你们拿到病历了吗  什么问题
Morning. You guys got the file. What's wrong?
之前的测验没有发现
Previous tests revealed nothing
任何可能引起腹部疼痛和情绪变化的问题
that would cause abdominal pain or the mood swings.
那我们的工作完成了
Then we're done.
想做点什么  看球还是逛动物园
What do you think? Ball game? Zoo?
什么都行  我只想跟你们一起
I don't care. I just want to hang with you guys.
有没有可能是吸毒
What about drugs?
他的入院毒性检测显示
His tox screen on admission
他体内有大剂量的水合氯醛
showed a massive amount of chloral hydrate.
不好意思  那是我弄的
Yeah. Sorry. That was me.
我不得不把他药翻了弄过来
I had to dope him up to get him in here.
这家伙认为自己没病
Guy doesn't think he's sick.
-谁认为他有  -他妻子
- Who does? - His wife.
和你一起生活过的女人
The woman you used to live with.
你说的是她印第安语昵称
That's her Indian name.
驾照上写的是史黛西
On her driver's license it's Stacy.
看来你是有话要说
I assume you have a point.
你信她  不信病人
You believe her over the patient himself.
所以我们才接这个病例
That's why we're taking this case.
要听真话吗  我脑子里一直有个声音
The truth? I hear voices all the time
指挥我做各种事情  是不是很疯狂
telling me to do stuff. It's crazy, huh?
不是"人人都会说谎"吗
What happened to "Everybody lies"?
我说谎了
I was lying.
去做各种乱七八糟的检测
Do the things... the blah, blah,
就是其他医生都会做的那些
blah, blah. All that stuff the other docs did.
如果是阴性  给他做腹部超声检查
If that's negative, ultrasound his belly.
如果还是阴性
If that's negative,
对他的腹部和骨盆分别做有无造影剂断层扫描
C.T. his abdomen and pelvis with and without contrast.
-我有没有漏掉什么  -厨房的水槽
- Did I miss anything? - Kitchen sink.
Everything but the kitchen sink
[意思是越轨的行为]
我们当然可以对那里也...小坏蛋
Well, we could certainly give that... Oh, you minx!
你一定是这样想的
What you're thinking is,
你会治好他  成为英雄  把她赢回来
you're going to save him, be a hero and win her back.
你这种扭曲的自恋每次都令我折服
It's always impressive, that level of twisted narcissism.
她已经结婚了  你还看不出来我早败了
She's married. Big clue I lost the game.
你不许靠近史黛西·华纳50英尺以内
You can't be within 50 feet of Stacy Warner.
她让我给她老公看病呢
Thought she wanted me to treat him.
看病归看病  离她远点
Treat the husband, stay away from the wife.
要是他俩靠近了呢  我怎么办
But what if they get close to each other? What do I do then?
你必须把他当做寻常病例对待
Hey. You have to treat this like a regular case.
做你自己
Be yourself...
冷漠  缺乏关怀  拒人千里
cold, uncaring, distant.
拜托  不要崇拜我
Please, don't put me on a pedestal.
我们对你的腹部做了CT
We C.T.'d your abdomen.
没有找出腹痛的症结
Nothing that would explain the stomach pain.
-下一步怎么办  -出院
- What's the next move? - Leaving.
我还要做多少检测
How many more tests do I need?
还要多少位医生诊断我没病
How many more doctors need to clear me
我们才能回归正常生活
before we can get back to our life?
-只有一位  -豪斯
- Just one. - House.
你一定觉得尴尬吧
It must be awkward being treated
被妻子以前交往的人治疗
by a man who used to be involved with your wife.
我这样分明没病
It's awkward being in a
却被困在医院里才叫尴尬
hospital when there's nothing wrong with me.
核磁共振查不出问题  说明他应该是健康的
M.R.A.'s were clean, which means he's probably fine.
他不像是有妄想症  也没有迹象...
He doesn't seem paranoid. He shows no signs of...
错  这只能说明我们没发现他的病症
No. It means we have no idea what's wrong with him.
本·戈尔茨坦说他的时间表排满了
Ben Goldstein says his schedule's locked.
最早要明天才能手术
He can't do it before tomorrow.
不行  就今天  打电话给他说我会安排
No. Today. Call him, tell him I'll make it work.
你要给他开刀
You're cutting him open?
等一下  没必要手术探查了
Oh, hold it. There's no need for exploratory surgery.
卡梅隆医生已经有诊断了
Dr. Cameron has a diagnosis.
没有  我只是认为
No, I just think it's premature
在确认他生病之前就做手术探查
and maybe irresponsible...
有欠考虑  而且可能有些不负责任
to do exploratory surgery before we know he's actually sick.
不对  现在把他列入临终护理名单
No, it's "Premature" To put him
才是"有欠考虑"
on a list for hospice care.
暗示我的行为不合理
And it's "maybe irresponsible"
才叫做"可能有些不负责任"
to imply my actions are not rationally supported.
我们的依据不过是他妻子...
All we have is his wife...
说他腹痛  我觉得足够了
Who says his stomach hurts. Works for me.
病人都不认为自己在生病  他怎么会同意
The patient doesn't even think he's sick. Why would he consent to...
他妻子是律师  很会劝人的
His wife's a lawyer. She's very convincing.
给戈尔茨坦打电话  手术一定要做
Call Goldstein. Surgery is on.
莱斯利诉莱斯利一案看似即将胜诉
Leslie versus Leslie seems to be right on point,
但我确信他们会争取...
but I'm sure they're going to try to distinguish it by...
抱歉  他们会着重于
Sorry. They'll try to distinguish it
指一名或几名法官持有的不同意多数法官意见
所达成的判决结果的意见
争取少数意见
relying on the minority opinion.
双份牛奶  不加糖
Double milk, no sugar.
我现在喜欢加糖了
I like sugar now.
别人会被你敲得心烦的
Some people would be annoyed by that.
你知道人们为什么坐在等侯室里吗
You know why people sit in waiting rooms?
好戏又要开始了
This is gonna be good.
人们认为靠手术室越近就表示
People think the closer they're sitting to the operating room,
他们对病人越关心
the more they care.
这也是我在这的原因
That's why I'm here.
所有人都看到我之前  我是不会离开的
I'm not moving until everybody sees me.
除了马克之外  你有和其他人交往吗
Are you doing anybody besides Mark?
这是个医学问题
It's a medical question.
因为如果我有的话  他的妄想就不是妄想了
Because if I am, his paranoia isn't paranoia.
它成了情有可原的反应而不是疾病症状
It's a justified response and therefore not a legitimate symptom.
我就知道你会明白
Knew you'd understand.
可是另一方面  如果这真是个医学问题
On the other hand, if it was really just a medical question,
你会派其他人来问
you would have sent one of your people.
招惹他们方便得很  为什么还来烦我呢
Why just push my buttons when you can push theirs too?
曼丁哥医生  去问那个妻子她有没有出轨
Hey, Dr. Mandingo, go ask the wife if she's been messin' around.
引出小说《曼丁哥人》
讲述阿拉巴马州种植园黑奴Mandinka的故事
你要问是因为  如果我有不忠行为
But you're asking because if I am... unfaithful,
我就有可能跟你上床
I might sleep with you.
答案是没有  我从不鬼混
The answer's no. I don't sleep around.
记得把这个写进他的医疗档案
Make sure you note that in his file.
华纳夫人
Mrs. Warner.
手术很成功  他在恢复室
The surgery went well. He's in Recovery.
你可以去看他了
You can see him now.
除了膀胱膨胀之外  戈尔茨坦一无所获
Goldstein found nothing but a distended bladder.
膀胱膨胀不是疼痛的起因
Neurogenic bladder isn't causing the pain.
也不会引起性格变化
It also doesn't cause personality changes.
换句话说  这完全证实了卡梅隆的诊断
On the other hand, it would completely account for Cameron's diagnosis.
病人是完全健康的
The patient's completely healthy.
把手术录像给我
Get me the video of the surgery.
曼丁哥医生  种植园需要你
Dr. Mandingo, you're needed at the plantation house.
好啦  别一起说
Well, don't everybody talk at once.
什么都没有
There's nothing there.
别盯着那个空又不空的酒瓶发呆  看屏幕
Stop looking at the suspiciously empty bottle and look at the screen.
这就是为什么我能拿高薪
Here's why I get the big bucks.
这里什么都没有
This is nothing.
什么都没有的加强版
An enhanced version of nothing.
这...才是问题所在
This... is the problem.
-难以置信  -肌纤维震颤
- Unbelievable. - Tremors in the muscle fiber.
这不是肠蠕动
That's not peristalsis.
是腹性癫痫
That's abdominal epilepsy.
意味着他有神经方面的问题
Means there's some sort of neurological problem.
他的大脑里有枚定时炸弹
A time bomb in his brain.
谁说什么都没有来着
I forget. Who said it was nothing?
我在他的脑电波中发现了
I saw a very small, diffuse abnormality
非常微弱的弥漫性异常  很可能是白质
in the brain waves. Probably white matter.
就是说他的神经轴突在死亡
Means his axonal nerves are dying.
所以他有神经性膀胱功能障碍
Explains the neurogenic bladder.
坏死的神经达到一定数量  他也会死
Enough nerves die, he dies.
大范围神经轴突死亡
Global axonal nerve death.
可能的成因是脑炎和阿兹海默症
Likely causes are encephalitis or Alzheimer's.
早发性阿兹海默症  最糟的可能
Early onset Alzheimer's. The worst.
他不会马上就死  但他会宁可早点死
He won't die right away. He'll just want to.
我去检测血液中阿兹海默症的蛋白标记
I'll check the blood for Alzheimer's protein markers.
据我所知  阿兹海默症有遗传组分
Last I heard, Alzheimer's had a genetic component.
病人有父母吗
Did the patient have parents?
父母死于车祸  没有痴呆病史
Parents died in a car crash. No history of dementia.
送脑脊液去做血球计数
Send C.S.F. for C.B.C.
和血清病毒筛查排除脑炎
and viral serologies to rule out encephalitis...
抽取Tau蛋白检测阿兹海默症
and get Tau proteins to check for Alzheimer's.
这些文件手感还是有点轻
And this still feels a little light.
我调来了完整的病史
I took a complete medical history.
查查他们的房子  带上贼小子
Check out their house. Take Sparky with you.
他们住在肖特山  有两小时路程呢
They live in Short Hills. Two hours away.
路费可以报销
You can expense the tolls.
你对病史不感兴趣
You're not interested in a medical history.
你就是个企图窥视前女友的偷窥狂
You're a Peeping Tom trying to spy on your ex.
她的秘密日记  重点找这个
Her secret diary... That's the main thing.
不过你们到她家的时候  也看一眼药柜
But as long as you're there, take a peek in the medicine cabinet.
检查毒素  重金属
check for toxins, heavy metals...
除脑炎和阿兹海默症之外
anything that might explain this
任何可以解释病症的东西
other than encephalitis or Alzheimer's.
路费记得要收据
And get receipts for the tolls.
在做午饭吗  我猜是给马克的
Making lunch? I assume that's for Mark.
我们已经了解了他的父母  其他亲属呢
We know about his parents. What about further back?
祖父母  叔伯  姨妈
Grandparents, uncles, aunts.
他们的健康如何
How was their health?
格雷戈不喜欢盲目猜测  他已经有结论了吧
Greg hates fishing. He's got a theory.
现在可能性最大的是阿兹海默症
Most likely candidate right now is Alzheimer's.
不可能  他没有记忆丧失
No. There's been no memory loss.
我意思是  他会忘记把钥匙放在哪里
I mean, he forgets where he left his keys,
可谁不会呢
but who doesn't?
有家族病史吗
Any family history?
哪种  脑子不正常的吗
Of... whacked-outness?
她妹妹投了纳德的票  还投了两次
His sister voted for Nader, twice.
拉尔夫·纳德(Ralph Nader)
屡败屡战  5次竞选美国总统
没别的了
That's about it.
豪斯的腿出事的时候
You were with House
你...和豪斯在一起吗
when it happened... to his leg?
你对他感兴趣
You're interested in him.
我们约会过一次
We went on one date.
不是很顺利
It didn't go very well.
我们的第一次约会也不顺利
Our first date didn't either.
我打算不再见他的
I was never gonna see him again.
结果一周之后我搬进了他家  一住就是5年
A week later, I moved in. Five years.
想知道些什么
What would you like to know?
他腿没坏之前是什么样的
What was he like before his leg?
跟现在差不多
Pretty much the same.
结果阴性  不是阿兹海默症
He's clear. No Alzheimer's.
嗯  我猜也是
Yeah, that's what I figured.
很有型的山地车  但是很久没用过了
Serious mountain bike. Hasn't been used in a while though.
他改做瑜伽了  全新的瑜珈毯和教程录像
He switched to yoga. Brand-new yoga mat and tape.
-说明他年纪大了  -也可能暗示着他背疼
- Man's getting older. - Or it might indicate back pain.
是的话他妻子会提到的
Wife would have mentioned it.
做瑜伽也是邂逅女士的好途径
Yoga's good for picking up the ladies too.
在自己家里做的时候除外
Not when you do it in your own home.
可能只是单纯的改变  不见得是症状
Change could be just a change, not a symptom.
奇斯
Chase.
亲爱的"豪小斯"们
"Dear 'House' boys,
为你们的非法搜查准备的点心
a snack for your highly illegal search.
希望你们喜欢燕麦提子饼  爱你们的史黛西
Hope you like oatmeal raisin. Love, Stacy".
书桌抽屉里找到的  藏在里面用纸盖着
In a desk drawer, hidden in the back under some papers.
私藏品
Secret stash.
安非他明  长期摄入可能导致神经中毒
Amphetamines. Regular use could lead to neurotoxicity.
解释了神经轴突损伤和性格变化问题
Explains the axonal nerve damage and the personality issues.
看看清楚  "开给W·布朗"
On the other hand, "Prescribed to W. Brown".
假名字  假处方
Fake name. Fake prescription.
有可能  不过处方医师的名字是真的
Could be, but the prescribing doc, his name's real.
这家伙前不久因为给高中生
This guy's just had his license pulled
非法开具处方被撤销了行医执照
for writing illegal prescriptions to high school kids.
马克是高中训导主任
Mark's a high school guidance counselor.
从布朗先生的生日可以看出他才17岁
And Mr. Brown's birth date makes him 17 years old.
你们想这会不会是
Do you think maybe these were
高中训导主任没收的物品呢
confiscated by a high school guidance counselor?
有其他发现吗
Anything else?
有  他放弃山地车改做瑜伽
Um, yeah, he switched from mountain biking to yoga.
-表明可能他...  -上年纪了
- Could indicate... - He's getting older.
脑脊液检测显示是脑炎吗
What did the C.S.F. Say about encephalitis?
不是  非常纯净
Said no. Champagne tap.
没有红细胞和白细胞  血清检测阴性
No red cells, no white cells. Serology's negative.
那我们又回到了阿兹海默症
Which means we're back to Alzheimer's.
我已经告诉她不是阿兹海默症了
I told her he didn't have it.
标记检测结果是阴性
The marker tests were negative.
你应当告诉她
Well, then you should have told her that
他将来还是有可能痴呆的
he could still have it.
PET扫描可以显示
PET scan will reveal any
大脑皮层代谢活动的任何变化
changing metabolic activity in the cerebral cortex.
给他做扫描  考考他的记忆
Run him through and check his memory.
我们给你注射一种名为F.D.D.N.P的化学标记
We're going to inject a chemical marker called F.D.D.N.P.
-之后我会问你一系列问题  -检测我的记忆
- Then I'm gonna ask you a series of questions. - Test my memory.
是的  但我们首先要检查大脑某些特定功能
Yeah, but first we're gonna map out some specific brain functions.
就像是开车之前先检查下发动机
You know, check out the engine before we take the car for a drive.
监督我工作吗
Checking up on me?
-我喜欢这里漂亮的小灯  -才怪
- I like all the pretty lights. - Yeah.
好了  我们开始
Okay. Here we go.
-你的全名是  -马克·华纳
- Your full name? - Mark Warner.
-你母亲还健在吗  -没有
- Is your mother living? - No.
大脑边缘系统完好
Limbic system's intact.
好  如果在路上捡到一封贴了邮票的信
Okay, say you find a stamped envelope on the street.
你会怎么做
What do you do?
-找个邮筒把它邮了  -多好一人呐
- Find a mailbox and mail it. - Geez. What a guy.
他的额叶比我健全多了
His frontal lobe is working way better than mine.
记得自己什么时候结婚的吗
Do you remember when you got married?
3年前的7月  谁在问话
Three years ago this July. Who is that?
怎么了  他的长期记忆可能会有问题
What? Could be a problem with his long-term memory.
-教堂里举行的盛大婚礼吗  -是豪斯吗
- Big church wedding? - Is that House?
-他能记住声音  -你这根本不是为了诊断
- He remembers voices. - This serves no diagnostic purpose.
我认为你测试边缘系统马虎了
I thought you skimped on the limbic system there.
情感反应  我只想周全点
Emotional reactions. I just want to be thorough.
无神论者新娘穿白色婚纱了吗
Did the atheistic bride wear a pretty white dress?
她当时有没有想着你
Was she thinking of you?
这是查我病需要知道的吗
Is that what you medically need to know?
你的新娘戴了什么首饰
What jewelry did your bride wear?
她从不戴任何首饰
She never wears any jewelry,
除了她母亲给她的十字架
except the cross her mother gave to her.
也不穿底裤  至少那天没穿
No underwear either, at least not that day.
我记得这个是因为
I remember 'cause she
她在车上就把漂亮的白婚纱撕开了
ripped her pretty white dress off in the car.
这是你想要的答案吗  医生
That the sort of answer you're looking for, Doctor?
-我想我惹他不高兴了  -你得马上停下
- I think I upset him. - You gotta stop this now.
我还记得是在巴黎度的蜜月
I remember the honeymoon was in Paris.
我记得这个是因为我们整整两周没有离开房间
I remember 'cause we didn't leave the room for two weeks.
-想听听细节吗  -有一点自我保护
- You want the details on that? - A little defensive.
在首先被人挑衅的情况下  不算是妄想症
It's not paranoia if someone's out to get you.
劈头盖脸地来了
Here we go.
他病了  焦虑多疑  你却拿我的事折腾他
He's sick, paranoid, and you keep hammering him about me?
那些问题是专门设计
The questions were designed to
用以确定他边缘系统的功能参数
define the operational parameters of his limbic system.
随你怎样狡辩  你只是在折磨他
Elevate the words all you want. You were just screwing with him.
真卑劣  即便以你的标准而言
Low, even by your standards.
出于医疗目的的折磨  这就是我的工作
Medical screwing. It's what I do.
那你干吗像个12岁小孩
Then why you run away like a 12-year-old.
躲到楼顶上  就像你一贯的作风
Go hide on the roof like you always do.
我有5年没上来这里了
I haven't been up here in five years.
我不知道他得了什么病
I don't know what's wrong with him.
不是阿兹海默症  不是脑炎
It's not Alzheimer's. It's not encephalitis.
不是环境毒素  不是免疫系统疾病
It's not environmental. It's not immunological.
所有的检测每次都是阴性
Every test is negative every time.
他完全是健康的
He's perfectly healthy,
可他的大脑正在坏死
but his brain is dying.
我从没想到...
It never occurred to me...
连你也会查不出问题
that you couldn't figure out what's wrong.
我还没有放弃
I haven't given up.
那我们怎么做
So what do we do?
我们等
We wait.
等什么
For what?
等待变化的出现
Something to change.
生活最大的悲剧之一就是  世事总是...
It's one of the great tragedies of life. Something always...
世事总无常
Something always changes.
护士
Nurse?
Nurse!
怎么了  出什么事了
What happened? What's wrong?
我的脚趾发麻  刺痛
My toes-- They were numb, tingling,
现在完全没知觉了
Then nothing.
也不疼  什么感觉都没了
No pain. Nothing.
别担心  他们会治好你的
It's okay. They're going to take care of you.
史黛西  我很害怕  握住我的手
I'm scared, Stacy. Hold my hand.
怎么了
What?
到底怎么回事
What's happening?
随着时间推移  他瘫痪了
Time marches on. He's paralyzed.
他的症状拟似外周围神经系统受到侵害
His symptoms mimic a peripheral nervous system under attack.
但他现在出现严重的肢体感觉异常
But he's experiencing significant paresthesias,
手脚均无法动弹
And he can't move his hands or toes.
外周神经系统受损
It's peripheral.
格林-巴利综合征攻击外周神经而非大脑
Guillain-Barre syndrome attacks there, not the brain.
不是  我已间接做过库姆斯氏试验
No. No. I already did an indirect Coombs' test.
没有凝集  没有抗体
No agglutination, no antibodies.
很主动嘛  好孩子
Initiative. Like that.
静脉注射免疫...
Start him on I.V. Immuno--
没有抗体就没有格林-巴利综合征  说完了
No antibodies means he doesn't have Guillain-Barre. Period.
完了?  应该还有别的可能性吧
Period? More like dot, dot, dot.
如果他体内有病毒而身体不产生抗体呢
What if he has the virus but isn't producing those antibodies?
得了吧  那样的机率...
Come on. The chances of that
没问你机率是多少  我是说"如果"
Didn't ask about the Vegas line. I said "What if".
那就说明他生病了  可他的身体却无动于衷
It would mean he's sick, and his body's not doing anything about it.
所以要么我们争取下
So we either fight it for him
要么这病就是致命的
or it's fatal.
"致命"这词多难听啊
Fatal sounds very bad to me.
没有抗体
Well, without the antibodies,
我们都无法测试
We can't even test for it.
无法确定我们诊断的对错
Don't know if we're right.
治疗方法也不是都那么危险
Treatment isn't all that dangerous.
血浆置换和静脉注射免疫球蛋白
Plasmapheresis and I.V.I.G.
如果起效  我们就对了
If it works, we're right.
如果他死了  就别有原因了
If he dies... it was something else.
那我的瘫痪可能只是一时的
So the paralysis might not be permanent.
但愿如此  可大脑令人捉摸不定
That's our hope, but the brain's tricky. You never know.
-怎么回事  -什么怎么回事
- What was that? - What?
他甩头的姿势还有那眼神
With the head. The look.
他只想跟我谈谈
He just wants to talk to me.
如果是关乎我的身体  他该跟我说
Well, if it was medical,he should be talking to me.
我就在门外
I'll be just outside the door.
走吧  去跟他聊吧
Leave! Go talk to him.
反正你早晚都会离开我的
You're going to leave me anyway.
不  不会的
No. That's not gonna happen.
你离开他  他瘸了
You left him,and he had a limp.
如果我无法行走  无法拥你入怀
If I can't walk or hold you?
亲爱的  我哪儿也不去
Honey, I'm not going anywhere.
我也不和他说话了
I'm not going to talk to him.
如果我不能自食其力
If I can't feed myself?
马克  你现在的感觉都是假的
Mark, what you're feeling--It's not real.
是病毒导致的错觉
It's the virus.
-马克  怎么回事  -马克
- Mark? What is it? - Mark?
他的气道正在关闭
His throat's closing up.
他无法呼吸  蓝色警报  快点
He can't breathe. Code blue! Hurry!
这是免疫球蛋白输液反应  立刻上肾上腺素
He's having a reaction to the I.V.I.G. I need epi, stat.
-我没法下喉镜  -住手
- I can't get the scope in his throat. - Stop that.
他对药物产生过敏  他快不行了
He's having an allergic reaction. He's crashing.
没有  你看他的生命体征
No, he's not. Look at his vitals.
血氧含量正常
O2 sats are within range.
我敢肯定他唯一的反常就是手心出汗
I'm betting the only abnormal sign is sweaty palms.
给他用2毫克的安定
Push two milligrams Ativan.
不是过敏  只是恐慌而已
No allergic reaction. Just a panic attack.
他显然是受惊了
Something obviously freaked him out.
现在我们能说话了吗
Can we talk now?
你就不能径直走进他的病房
You couldn't just come into the room?
已经有5个人来探望过他了
He's had five visitors drive down.
我一个都不认识
I didn't recognize any of them.
还有6个人给他送了花  糖果和泰迪熊
Six more have sent him flowers, candy and a teddy bear,
他定倍感欣慰
Which I'm sure he finds very comforting.
可卡片上那些名字我也一个都不认识
But I didn't recognize any of the names on the cards.
惊人啊  马克有朋友
Shockingly, Mark has friends,
我还结交了一些新朋友
and I have some new ones.
你有新朋友  我丝毫不感到震惊
No, it's not shocking that you have new friends,
令我震惊的是  你舍弃你所有的旧朋友
But it is shocking that you apparently dumped all your old ones.
-我没有 -是吗  我也这么想的
- I haven't. - No, I didn't think so.
我猜你只是没有通知他们你来了这里
I just think you didn't tell any of them that you were down here.
为什么这么做呢
Now, why would that be?
-你在忙什么  -要等会儿
- What are you up to? - It's gonna take a little while.
为什么你没告诉你的老朋友
Why would you not tell your oldest friends...
你把马克送到
that you were taking Mark to
普波教学医院救治
Princeton Plainsboro Teaching Hospital to try to save his life?
我很忙  没时间一一通知
I've been busy. I haven't kept track of who knows what.
瞧  我的老朋友要我小心点
See, my old friends are telling me to be careful.
他们似乎认为
They seem to think--
是他  是他送的熊
He. And he sent me the bear.
明白了
Figures.
他似乎认为
He seems to think
我对你还没忘怀
that I'm not over you...
和你共处一室有点危险
And that it might be dangerous for me to spend time with you.
我猜你的朋友或许有类似的担忧
I'm thinking your friends might have similar concerns,
所以你没告诉他们你在这里和在我一起
And so you didn't tell them you'd be here with me.
你想说什么  我还爱着你吗
What's your point? That I'm still in love with you?
我该抛弃垂死的丈夫
I should abandon my dying husband,
和你一起去里约热内卢
and we should head for Rio.
不是
No.
格雷戈  我感激你为我们做的事情
Greg I appreciate what you are doing for us
不过看来威尔森说的没错
but I think maybe Wilson's right.
或许你该和我保持距离
Maybe you should just stay away from me.
怎么了
What's up?
爱那个熊呗  可爱死了
Love the bear. It's adorable.
我老婆会杀了我的
My wife's gonna kill me.
今晚我们有客  她亲自下厨
We're having company. She cooked.
刚拿到马克的最新血检报告
I got Mark's latest blood work.
治疗毫不起效
He's not responding to treatment.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我倒挺开心的
I was happy.
他是我的病人
He's my patient.
而且他是个好人  说不定还是个大好人
I'm sure he's a good guy. He's probably a great guy.
显然比我好得多得多
He's apparently a much better guy than I am.
可我心里面竟有点希望他死
And some part of me wants him to die.
只不过我搞不清
I'm just not sure
我这样到底是我因为想和她重温旧梦
if it's because...I want to be with her,
还是因为我希望她痛苦不堪
Or it's because I want her to suffer.
介意我和史黛西聊一会儿吗
Hey. Is it okay if I talk to Stacy for a minute?
我就在门外  亲爱的
I'll be just outside, honey.
你们相处的挺融洽
You two are good together.
你对马克一无所知
You know nothing about Mark.
他带你去了巴黎
He took you to Paris.
我觉得这就挺好
That's good enough for me.
我们从没去过巴黎
We never went to Paris.
你们度蜜月的时候去的
Your honeymoon.
巴黎一直是你的梦之城
It's been your dream city.
你从16岁开始就憧憬巴黎
You wanted to go since you were 16.
他实现了你的心愿
He actually took you.
不啊 那时我得工作
No, I had to work.
我们在纽约待了一晚就回肖特山了
We spent the night in New York. Then we went back to Short Hills.
怎么回事
What is it?
马克什么时候不骑山地车转而练瑜伽的
When did Mark switch from mountain biking to yoga?
大概一个月前吧
About a month ago.
差不多是他生病的时候
The same time he started getting sick.
这说明什么问题
What does that mean?
又多了两个病症
We have two more symptoms.
我们曾问过病人一些问题
The patient was asked a series of questions
以测试他的脑功能
to determine the functionality of his brain.
-你拷问了他史黛西的情况  -随便啦
- You grilled him about Stacy. - Whatever.
关键是
Yeah, the point is,
我们诊断需要知道的他其实全都告诉我们了
he told us everything we need to know to diagnose him.
前提是把你的超炫PET扫描当测谎仪来用
That is, if we use your fancy PET scan as a lie detector.
瞧  说谎是个很费脑子的过程
See, it's a very creative process, lying.
说真相的过程倒是容易许多  看这里
Now, telling the truth is a much simpler process. See here.
问题9
Question nine.
马克长篇大论了一番
This is where Mark gives a long, rambling answer about
他和史黛西的巴黎之旅
taking Stacy to Paris.
PET扫描的结果是什么
What does the PET scan say?
脑活跃程度最小  只有额叶和颞叶
Minimal involvement. Just the frontal and temporal lobes.
他说他去了巴黎  PET扫描确认属实
He said he went to Paris, and the PET confirms it.
那又怎样
So, what?
他们根本没去
They didn't go.
他们没去巴黎  可马克的大脑认为
They didn't go to Paris, and yet Mark's brain apparently thinks...
他真的花了40法郎游览了巴士底监狱
that he really did spend 40 francs on a tour of the bastille.
好了  现在的症状是间歇伴有腹部疼痛
So we have an intermittent syndrome that presents with abdominal pain,
多神经病变  妄想症
Polyneuropathy, paranoia...
以及幻觉
And delusions.
急性间歇性卟啉病有个特征
Now, here's the thing about Acute Intermittent Porphyria.
它潜伏在阴暗的巷子里  伺机扑向你
It'll jump you in a dark alley,
暴打你一顿之后  把你扔那儿流血
beat the crap out of you, leave you bleeding.
不过它戴了手套  所以没有留下指纹
But it wears gloves, so no fingerprints.
血检查不出  尿检也查不出
Doesn't show up in blood tests, urine tests, nothing...
除非你在案发现场抓它个正着
Unless you catch it red-handed in the middle of an attack.
可急性间歇性卟啉病还有其他症状
But there are other symptoms of A.I.P.
-比如说呢  -对光敏感
- Such as? - Light sensitivity.
是啊  生这种病的一大悲剧
Yeah. One of the true tragedies of this condition...
就是它整得你直想把你崭新拉风的山地车扔车库里
is it makes you want to stick your cool new mountain bike in the garage...
躲在屋子里做运动  比如说瑜伽
And take up an indoor sport like, say, yoga.
开始治疗  用血红素和葡萄糖
Start the treatment. Hematin and glucose.
你现在给他用血红素  万一你错了
If you give him Hematin now and you're wrong,
他今天就没命
he dies today.
要确诊急性间歇性卟啉病只有一个办法
There's only one way to confirm A.I.P.,
在发病时采集尿样化验
urine sample made during the attack.
可我们没办法预见他发病的时间
And there's no way to predict when he'll have another attack.
谁说没办法
Sure there is.
急性间歇性卟啉病有其特定的发病诱因
Acute Intermittent Porphyria has very specific triggers.
巴比妥酸盐  酒精
Barbiturates, alcohol,
高浓度蛋白质  都会使患者发病
high levels of protein will set off an attack.
-那马克是因为什么发病呢  -完全不知道
- Which trigger do you think set off Mark's? - Not the faintest idea.
所以我就三者合一  给他上一套餐
That's why I'm gonna give him the combo plate. All of it.
那如果他有这病  你诱导发病
So if he has this, and you trigger an attack,
他的情况就会更糟  对吗
the attack makes him worse, right?
对  但到时我们就知道病因  就能下药了
Yeah. But then we'll know what it is and we can treat it.
可我要没这病
But if I don't have this thing
你又给我打了那针  会怎么样
and you give me that shot, what happens?
不知道  我们不知道你的病因
No idea. If we don't know what's messing up your brain,
就不能预料反应
we don't know how you'll react.
好  让我和他单独说会话
Okay, I-- I need a minute with my husband.
他不同意触发病症
He doesn't want the trigger.
他想再等等  看你们有没有新的说法
He wants to wait, see if we can come up with another explanation.
如果真是这个病  他还能活多久
If it is A.I.P., how much time does he have?
难说  下次发病可能就会致命
No idea. Next attack could be fatal.
可能半年后  也可能是五分钟
Could be six months from now. Could be five minutes from now.
-我要你继续检测  -行
- I want you to test him. - Fine.
我会检测羟甲基胆色烷合酶的突变情况
I'll send for an H.M.B-synthase mutation.
基因测试  一个月出结果
Genetic test. Lab will get back to us in a month.
注射吧  让他发病
Give him the cocktail, set off an attack.
-不  -为什么
- No. - Why not?
因为他不同意
Because he doesn't want me to.
我不会告你的  也不会举报你
I'm not gonna sue you. I'm not gonna report you.
-他可能会  -他都瘫了
- He might. - He's paralyzed.
你要治不好他  他什么都干不了
Either you cure him, or he won't be writing any letters.
-我不会这么做的  -为什么呀
- I'm not gonna do it. - Why not?
不管你怎么问  不会就是不会
You keep asking me that question. My answer doesn't change.
情况我跟他说清楚了  由他选择
I gave him the parameters. It's his call.
你想让他死
You want him to die.
我查出病因  仁至义尽了
I diagnosed him. I did my job.
要霸王硬上弓  硬逼人治疗
You want somebody to tie him down and force him into treatment,
你比我在行
you're way better at that than I am.
这是为你的腿报复我吗  你就这么小心眼
Is that what this is? Payback for your leg?
说多少次了  我捡回你一条命
How many times have we been over this? I saved your life.
-算是吧  -你要害死我丈夫来教训我吗
- Yeah, maybe. - You're gonna kill my husband to teach me a lesson?
我没有  是他太固执太笨
No. He's gonna die 'cause he's too stubborn
要害死自己
to make the right choice.
这可是你的地盘
Now we're in your territory.
我是在尊重你丈夫的决定
I'm respecting your husband's decision.
这有什么奇怪的
I don't see why you've got a problem with that.
你胡说八道
Because it's crap.
平时你对病人连恐吓带威胁  还满嘴谎话
Because you browbeat patients, intimidate them, lie to them.
你主意定了  才不管他们怎么决定
If you think you're right, you don't give a damn what they think.
恐吓威胁我也会
I did what you do all the time.
不过跟你不同  我只威胁你一个人
The only difference is, I did it to you.
他永远不会原谅你
He'll never forgive you.
没错  他不会
Yeah. He will.
-还是没变化  -没有恶化吗
- Still no change. - He's not getting worse?
没有  毫无变化
No. No change at all.
急性间歇性卟啉病就是这样吧
And that's consistent with A.I.P., right?
-发病前一切稳定  -对
- Until he has another attack, his condition's stable. - Yeah.
-马克  你还是...-我不想试
- Mark, you've got to... - I don't want to take that test,
我要等他们确诊
not until they're sure.
-你不了解格雷戈  -就你了解
- You don't know Greg. - Not like you do.
我就见过他一次  还被他下了药
I only met him when he drugged me.
哎哟  羞愧死我了
Boy, are my ears burning.
-你拿的什么  -套餐呗
- What's that? - Cocktail hour.
我们可不歧视残疾人
Just 'cause you can't hoist a few
给你也来一份
doesn't mean you should be left out.
-你别碰我  -马克
- Get away from me. - Mark,
如果这是他的诊断...
if this is what he thinks is wrong with you--
-你信他不信我吗  -他是专业医生
- You trust his judgment more than mine? - His medical judgment.
-你要赌我的命  -我愿意
- And you'd bet my life on that? - I would.
可我不愿意
I don't.
聪明
Smart.
可惜你瘫了
It's too bad you're paralyzed.
叮咚  呼叫福曼医生
Bing! Paging Dr. Foreman.
出去吧  少管闲事
Leave the room. It's not your problem.
你得征求病人同意
You need the consent from him.
可医生  他脑筋糊涂哎
But, Doc, he ain't right in the head.
那就要法院批准
Then you need a court order.
行啊  你俩申请去  我们等着
Okay. Then get one. We'll wait here.
我保证不乱来
I won't do nothin'.
嚄  就喜欢三剑客的范儿
Oh! Love the Musketeer thing.
-我都起鸡皮疙瘩了  -把注射器给我
- I got goose bumps. - Give me the syringe.
求你了  如果你猜对了  他只能拼一把
Please. If you're right, this may be his only shot.
跟你商量商量
So what's your plan?
你对付高大威猛的黑小子
You take the big dark one,
我来搞定这小姑娘
I've got the little girl,
至于澳洲小白脸
and the Aussie will
一打起来马上跟吓破胆的小袋熊一样一溜烟跑没影
run like a scared wombat if things turn rough.
我做不到
I can't do it.
你这混蛋
You son of a bitch!
迅雷不及掩耳吧
See what I did there?
什么时候会发病
When does it happen?
如果真是急性间歇性卟啉病
If he had A.I.P.,
应该已经发病了
should've already happened.
-各有不同嘛  -情况不妙
- Everyone's different. - This is not good.
他可能会血管栓塞  心动过速  还可能中风
He could have an embolism, tachycardia, stroke.
怎么了  注射两毫克安定
What's happening? Two milligrams of Ativan.
是发病了吗
Is that an attack?
-给  -不行  会污染尿样
- Here. - No. You'll pollute the sample.
奇斯  从导尿管取样
Chase, get urine from the catheter.
他没发病  他中风了
It's not an attack! He's stroking.
他需要安定
He needs Ativan!
不是中风  出现高幅慢波阵只是因为血管痉挛
This is not a stroke. The delta-wave burst is just a vasospasm.
导尿管掉了  没法取样了
Catheter's out. There's no way to collect the sample.
心跳降到40几  心动过缓  他不行了
Heart rate's in the 40s. Bradycardia. We're losing him.
-按住他  -总之给他点什么
- Hold him down. - Give him something!
-止痛药用光了  -你错了
- No painkillers. - You were wrong.
直接从膀胱取样  新鲜纯净没得比
Straight from the bladder. That's as fresh as it gets.
等什么  赶紧上安定呀
Would you give him the Ativan already.
何必让他受活罪呢
He doesn't need to be awake for this.
还黄澄澄的
It's still yellow.
让开
Move.
-干嘛  -加盏灯有什么用
- What? - You think another light's gonna make the difference?
有机化学原理  光照越足  氧化越快
Organic chem-- more light, more oxidation.
脑瓜转起来没
Does that ring any bells?
开始用药  150毫克葡萄糖
Start the patient on 150 milligrams glucose,
75毫克血红素
75 milligrams Hematin.
要不要掰手指
You wanna thumb wrestle?
来吧
Come on.
-我还是讨厌那疯子  -我懂
- He's still a maniac. - I know.
豪斯医生
Dr. House?
他怎么样了
How's he doing?
好得不能再好了
Never better.
我原以为
I thought...
你被伤得太重  无法再爱了
you were too screwed up to love anyone.
可我错了
I was wrong.
你只是爱着别人
You just couldn't love me.
挺好
That's good.
我为你高兴
I'm happy for you.
你治好了他
You fixed him.
这没啥
De nada.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你说对了
You were right.
他会康复的
He's gonna be fine.
不  说的是我
No. About me.
我还没放下你
I'm not over you.
你...一直是我心里那个人
You were-- you were the one.
永远都是
You always will be.
但我不能跟你在一起
But I can't be with you.
那么就是说  你爱的是我
So I'm the guy,
却嫁了另一个
but you want the other guy,
那个成为你的丈夫  却不会得到你的爱的人
who, by definition, can never be the guy.
你最妙的就是这笃定自己没错的神气劲
What's so great about you is you always think you're right.
最气人的是
And what's so frustrating
大部分时间你还真没错
about you is you are right so much of the time.
你才华横溢
You are brilliant,
幽默  不单调  还很性感
funny, surprising, sexy.
但跟你在一起  我很孤独
But with you, I was lonely.
跟马克呢  就还能保留自我
And with Mark, there's room for me.
懂了
Okay.
我有事跟你说
I want to run something by you.
我不会再跟你上床了  再也不了
I will not have sex with you! Not again.
第一次就够糟的了
It was miserable that first time.
你们管理层真是饥不择食
All that desperate administrative need.
史黛西的丈夫
Stacy's husband is going
需要留院密切观察
to need close monitoring at the hospital,
而医院肯定用得上她
and since we can definitely use her back here,
我准备雇她做法律顾问
I've offered her a job-- general counsel.
她答应了吗
Did she say yes?
她说你同意她才来
She said only if it was okay with you.
你同不同意啊
Yes or no?
行啊  好
Fine. Good.